This Thanksgiving, carve out some family time.
Flesh & Blood is a horror, thriller film directed by Patrick Lussier.
Kimberly, a teenager suffering from agoraphobia, has not left
the house since her mother's unsolved murder.
On the eve of Thanksgiving, she begins to suspect that the safe harbor
of home and her doting father may be a dangerous mirage.
Kimberly Tooms, played by Diana Silvers.
Henry Tooms, played by Dermot Mulroney.
Dr. Helen Saunders, played by Tembi Locke.
Rose Tooms, played by Meredith Salenger.
Officer Foster, played by Lavetta Cannon.
Officer Banks, played by Heidi Sulzman.
Flesh and Blood is a 1985 erotic historical adventure film directed by Paul Verhoeven, and starring Rutger Hauer,
Jennifer Jason Leigh, Tom Burlinson, Susan Tyrrell, Ronald Lacey, Bruno Kirby and Jack Thompson.
The script was written by Verhoeven and Gerard Soeteman.
The story is set in 1501 in early modern Italy, and follows two warring
groups of mercenaries and their longstanding quarrel.
The script is partly based on unused material for the Dutch television series
Floris, which was the debut for Verhoeven, Soeteman and Hauer.
The film, originally titled God's Own Butchers, was also known
as The Rose and the Sword on early VHS releases.
It was Verhoeven's first English-language film.
Upon its release in August 1985, Flesh and Blood was a box office bomb,
earning only US$100,000 on a US$6.5 million production budget.
The film has since garnered a small cult following.
The director's biographer called it "a crucial Verhoeven film, because the fight between logic and spirituality is one
that is very familiar to the director; these are the elements still fighting for priority in his own mind."
The film explores themes of therapist, holiday,
thanksgiving, murder, agoraphobia.
The tone is dark and intense.